{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "The full form of Ni-NTA is",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Nickel-nitrilotrioacetic acid (NTA)",
        "b": "Nickel-nitrilotriacetic acid (NTA)",
        "c": "Nickel-triacetic acid (NTA)",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
     
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "Ni-NTA Agarose is used for the purification of recombinant proteins expressed in",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Bacteria",
        "b": "Insect",
        "c": "Mammalian cells",
        "d": "All of the above"
      },
     
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which amino acid in the recombinant protein binds to Nickel, in Ni-NTA affinity chromatography",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Histidine",
        "b": "Tryptophan",
        "c": "Alanine",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
     
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "4. The Ni-NTA resins exhibit high affinity and selectivity for 6xHis-tagged recombinant proteins where 6xHis-tag can be fused to its ",
      "answers": {
        "a": "N-terminus",
        "b": "C-terminus",
        "c": "Both a and b",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
     
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "5. Why does loading/wash buffer contain a low concentration of imidazole",
      "answers": {
        "a": "To remove 6xHis-tag recombinant protein",
        "b": "To elute weak binding contaminant proteins",
        "c": "To increase the binding between Nickel and 6xHis-tag recombinant protein",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
     
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Why do we add a higher concentration of imidazole in the elution buffer",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Because it competes with the recombinant proteins for nickel binding",
        "b": "Because it acts as an inhibitor for recombinant proteins and nickel binding",
        "c": "To stabilize the recombinant proteins and nickel binding",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
     
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "7. Nickel in Ni-NTA affinity chromatography interacts with how many histidines of a His-tag  ",
      "answers": {
        "a": "One ",
        "b": "Six",
        "c": "Four",
        "d": "Two"
      },
     
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "8. Nickel makes coordinate bond with the ……………… of histidine",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Side chain",
        "b": "Amino group",
        "c": "Carboxyl group",
        "d": "All of the above"
      },
     
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "9. Why protein does not bind to the Ni-NTA matrix in an acidic pH range",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Because it can cause protonation of the histidine side chains and thus prevent the histidine residues from coordinating with nickel",
        "b": "Because it can cause deprotonation of the histidine side chains and thus prevent the histidine residues from coordinating with nickel",
        "c": "Because protein aggregates",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
     
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "10. What are different methods of elution of recombinant protein from Ni-NTA column other than imidazole",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Low pH buffe",
        "b": "By competition with histidine",
        "c": "Both a and b",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
     
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    }
  ]
}
